[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe2", "question": "What did the Emancipation Proclamation do?", "answer": "It freed all the slaves in the Confederacy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c520", "question": "Polaris is commonly known as what star?", "answer": "The North Star", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c7", "question": "What nickname was given to the brutal Royal Irish Constabulary Reserve Force in 1920?", "answer": "Black and Tans", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81fdfd0de9af39e9d469a", "question": "What year did Amazon.com make its first sale?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16a79f7c52aae91cc07dd", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\", who is the Kind of Naples?", "answer": "Alonso", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cd40d5a685cf15b733e9892", "question": "Why did the Mongolians fail to invade Japan?", "answer": "Because of a typhoon called \"kamikaze\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ded01fea2747c8aff16d23", "question": "In which sport is the America's Cup awarded?", "answer": "Sailboat racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b1", "question": "What was Aerosmith\u2019s first Top 10 song on the Billboard charts?", "answer": "Dream On", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c754", "question": "What layer of the atmosphere is closest to the earth?", "answer": "The Troposphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9057701dd7bf43be5e87c", "question": "What does \u00a0\"alea iacta est\" translate into?", "answer": "The die is cast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a8", "question": "What musical's show-stopping songs include \"Mr. Cellophane\" and \"Razzle Dazzle\"?", "answer": "Chicago's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1e", "question": "What period preceded Picasso's \"Rose Period\"?", "answer": "Blue Period", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339623", "question": "What Robert Rodriguez film followed \"El Mariachi\"?", "answer": "Desperado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a081", "question": "What is the name of the lead singer for the Canadian rock band Rush?", "answer": "Geddy Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e75", "question": "What superteam includes Robin, Kid Flash, Aqualad and Wonder Girl?", "answer": "The Teen Titans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c722", "question": "What company introduced the first hand-held calculator in 1967?", "answer": "Texas Instruments", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad35", "question": "Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. received his Ph.D. from which school?", "answer": "Boston University", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd969ce23c87fd04dd15e0d", "question": "What was Thomas Edison's nickname?", "answer": "The Wizard of Menlo Park", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395aa", "question": "Who played Elliot Ness in the 1987 movie \"The Untouchables\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44b", "question": "On August 2, 1876, Jack McCall gunned down which famous lawman?", "answer": "Wild Bill Hickok", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c347", "question": "What is the name of the test to determine whether a computer could convincingly imitate a human?", "answer": "The Turing test", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f71", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Jim Douglas?", "answer": "Herbie, the Love Bug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb90", "question": "What four-word expression meaning \"everything\" is derived from the three main parts of a musket?", "answer": "Lock, stock and barrel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfbe8e003d27d341092bd0", "question": "Why are Amsterdam's buildings so narrow?", "answer": "A tax loophole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be56", "question": "What common lasagna ingredient is actually a by-product of mozzarella?", "answer": "Ricotta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c76", "question": "What horror movie title character will appear if you chant his name five times in a mirror?", "answer": "Candyman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32c", "question": "What year was the film \"48 Hrs.\", starring Eddie Murphy and Nick Nolte released?", "answer": "1982", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffe4bd247818f5674af01b4", "question": "What is the name of the book the movie \"Goodfellas\" is based on?", "answer": "\"Wiseguy: Life in a Mafia Family\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c3", "question": "Which alphabet consists of just dots?", "answer": "Braille", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bb64fb6c85e9e634ff54", "question": "Whose fifth album was called \"Different Class\"?", "answer": "Pulp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b27afb6c85e9e634ff3e", "question": "Who was king of England from 1422 until 1461?", "answer": "Henry Vl", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abdd", "question": "Which famous city bridge is known locally as \"The Coathanger\"?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour Bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd467e347d002c297e4af", "question": "Who was the first monarch of the House of Windsor?", "answer": "George V", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff9", "question": "Who won a Nobel Peace Prize in 1906 for his work at ending the Russo-Japanese War?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071ec93745b36be73039e5", "question": "In the \"Revival\" comic book series, what is the family name of the brothers who try to sell parts of the revivers?", "answer": "Check", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c081", "question": "People with a lot of hair are said to suffer from what?", "answer": "Hypertrichosis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0c2a469bb8041d07a04e", "question": "Which U.S. sandwich shop originally went by the name \"Pete's Super Submarines\"?", "answer": "Subway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d33", "question": "What surgeon on the TV show ER shares his name with a \"Warlord of Mars\" created by Edgar Rice Burroughs?", "answer": "John Carter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd82165d0de9af39e9d46a5", "question": "As of 2020, who is the longest serving Chief Justice of the U.S. Supreme Court?", "answer": "John Marshall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2a0ec9bff04efae6d75b", "question": "Who had a No. 1 hit in 1965 with the song \"I'm Alive\"?", "answer": "The Hollies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9df61e748bb36357acde8", "question": "The City of Hot Coffee is in what US state?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8ce6d94b094db915830a7", "question": "What is the Italian word for ice cream?", "answer": "Gelato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5901d794709c1c34536e6ea3", "question": "What was the first flavor of the malt beverage named \"Zima\"?", "answer": "Lemon-Lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c738", "question": "Dry Ice is the solid form of what chemical compound?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd0", "question": "What NBA star made an ill-fated trip to Eagle, Colorado, in 2003 for knee surgery?", "answer": "Kobe Bryant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7abc516490a8cc1a6e5299", "question": "What is the maximum high score that can be shown on the screen in the video game \"Pac-Man\"?", "answer": "999,990 points", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f1676af7c52aae91cc07b9", "question": "The Republic of Guinea-Bissau is located on which African coast?", "answer": "Western coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e90fe44d7247dfc0fa00308", "question": "Who was the first character Walt Disney created?", "answer": "Oswald the Lucky Rabbit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ada201dd7bf43be5e77c", "question": "What does the abbreviation DVD stand for?", "answer": "Digital Versatile Device", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de3", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"muffin\"?", "answer": "German", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323268bf195a31e15d7390", "question": "What country is directly west of Spain?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67d", "question": "For what game were two jokers originally included in a standard deck of playing cards?", "answer": "Euchre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e4d", "question": "What eccentric artist based his famous moustache on that worn by painter Diego Velazquez?", "answer": "Salvador Dali", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892c", "question": "In the novel \"Fahrenheit 451\", what does the title refer to?", "answer": "The temperature at which paper burns", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf4", "question": "Where did the Gilmore Girls reside?", "answer": "Stars Hollow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6f", "question": "Edam cheese comes from what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f8", "question": "What is the capital of Gabon?", "answer": "Libreville", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c77f877e98cb977789cf", "question": "Why is the Bronx called the Bronx?", "answer": "After a landowner named Jonas Bronck", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963b", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Faline?", "answer": "Bambi's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d47438f8e329de4f87789a", "question": "The Bunya Pine tree is native to which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930d", "question": "In the movie \"Rambo:First Blood\", how many people did John Rambo kill?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa4", "question": "What musical is the sequel to \"The Phantom of the Opera\"?", "answer": "Love Never Dies", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7b", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The African Queen\" set?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d5", "question": "Which band is known in Spain as U-Dos?", "answer": "U2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897c", "question": "How many puppies did Missis Pongo give birth to in the book \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "15", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339801", "question": "What looks like a saxophone but sounds like a harmonica?", "answer": "Goofus or Couesnophone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aff", "question": "What was Radar's real first name on the sitcom \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Walter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"Hello, beautiful. No ring, I see. So you are only arranged to be married.\"?", "answer": "Apu Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdd3eec223966ae8f8902", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef66216ce05a3942286e77", "question": "Who voiced Miss Piggy originally?", "answer": "Frank Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea8339ff048f679a45ac26", "question": "What is the fastest sense?", "answer": "Hearing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe903d901dd7bf43be5e871", "question": "Which U.S. federal agency provides protection for the federal judiciary?", "answer": "United States Marshals Service", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfdf", "question": "Doraphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fur", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b9", "question": "What was Peter Gunn's girlfriend's name?", "answer": "Edie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e89", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Griffin?", "answer": "Eagle and lion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b988", "question": "By what name is Mardi Gras known in Britain?", "answer": "Shrove Tuesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d8", "question": "What Jane Austen book has many parallels with \"Bridget Jones's Diary\" including the main male character?", "answer": "Pride and Prejudice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b885e662d71a53651025", "question": "Which German painter was sometimes court painter to King Henry VIII of England after 1536?", "answer": "Hans Holbein the Younger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008aafcf842fa4c4ba9692", "question": "Who released the 1979 song \"Rock 'n' Roll High School\"?", "answer": "The Ramones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded09aea2747c8aff16d2a", "question": "What is extracted from the ore cassiterite?", "answer": "Tin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c00b", "question": "Rioja wine comes from which country?", "answer": "Spain\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e95957ccba3ffe45786e1", "question": "Which Verdi opera features the aria \"La donna e mobile\"?", "answer": "Rigoletto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a1e1d9cb5a031299b74573c", "question": "What century did the Europeans dicover the Okapi?", "answer": "20th Century", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66246a5bfecdd737e0843", "question": "Who was the oldest Chief Justice appointed to the U.S. Supreme Court?", "answer": "Harlan Stone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb0", "question": "What is the name for a gin martini garnished with a pickled onion instead of an olive?", "answer": "Gibson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1ac7baab681b09292196", "question": "Which car is considered to be the first hot hatchback, introduced in the 1970s?", "answer": "The Simca 1100 TI", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a629", "question": "What U.S. state capital city is located at the southern shores of Lake Oahe?", "answer": "Pierre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2c", "question": "What novel by Lucy Maud Montgomery became Canada's longest-running main stage musical?", "answer": "Anne of Green Gables", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f3f3eaf848b908361b86b", "question": "What amusement ride was first ridden in 1893 at the World's Columbian Exposition in Chicago?", "answer": "The Ferris Wheel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe734f2eec85e375820b240", "question": "What prison held Rudolf Hess after World War II?", "answer": "Spandau Prison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d9", "question": "Which is heavier, a baseball or a softball?", "answer": "A softball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ab", "question": "How old was Humphrey Bogart when he died in 1957?", "answer": "57", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c682", "question": "In Newton's second law of motion force is equal to mass times what?", "answer": "Acceleration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd81d35d0de9af39e9d468c", "question": "What is the largest pyramid?", "answer": "Pyramid of Cholula", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c5b", "question": "What weather phenomenon swept Dorothy Gale to the Land of Oz?", "answer": "A tornado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb123f83302ff91e464a4", "question": "What brand of stapler is Milton Waddams attached to in the film \"Office Space\"?", "answer": "Swingline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989aa3ccb8751d53e7d7602", "question": "Who served as the United States Ambassador to Japan from 2013-2017?", "answer": "Caroline Bouvier Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8a0aec223966ae8f882d", "question": "What was the first animated film to be nominated for Best Picture at the Academy Awards?", "answer": "\"Beauty and the Beast\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af03", "question": "The Declaration of Independence was adopted in the east room of what building?", "answer": "Independence Hall", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f4", "question": "Who\u2019s Fred Flintstone\u2019s best friend?", "answer": "Barney Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5cb", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Pine Tree State\"?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977c", "question": "What is the name of Kane's private estate in Citizen Kane?", "answer": "Xanadu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5afad88e430e050a5df0d112", "question": "Which brand of soda was the second to be produced by The Coca-Cola Company?", "answer": "Fanta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa71", "question": "Rioja wine comes from which country?", "answer": "Spain\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc4", "question": "What is a fairy ring made of?", "answer": "Mushrooms", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a4", "question": "Natalie Coughlin won six medals in what sport at the 2008 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Swimming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93b", "question": "What US state is home to the singer of Stephen Foster's \"Oh! Susanna\"?", "answer": "Alabama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67b", "question": "What bay does the San Mateo bridge cross?", "answer": "San Francisco Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133947e", "question": "In the movie \"Legally Blonde\", what LSAT score does Elle need to get into Harvard?", "answer": "175", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068132ff9c0647b50a8092", "question": "Who plays the role of Elliot Alderson in the TV show \"Mr. Robot\"?", "answer": "Rami Malek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e427fe83fe1f2a824bae", "question": "The Battle of Kursk is best described as what type of battle?", "answer": "A tank battle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338906", "question": "Who wrote the music for the stage version of \"Billy Elliot\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff7c28f2b316f4693fb67a1", "question": "Which candy company is known as the primary producer of \"conversation hearts\" in the United States?", "answer": "The New England Confectionary Company or NECCO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b999", "question": "What is the capital of Nigeria?", "answer": "Abuja", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3b", "question": "What plant is used to make tequila?", "answer": "Blue agave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24d", "question": "Do sea gulls drink sea water?", "answer": "Yes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef66126ce05a3942286e75", "question": "What state inspired Joni Mitchell's \"Big Yellow Taxi\"?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b7e1e662d71a53651019", "question": "In the late 1700's Francisco Goya took a job drawing for what type of royal factory?", "answer": "Tapestry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3b36c73aa70ea0b70ae5", "question": "What is the earliest known walled city?", "answer": "Fortifications unearthed in Jericho dating back to 6800 B.C. confirm that it is the earliest known walled city.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc1b8ec223966ae8f886d", "question": "The three actors who starred as Magneto, Iron Man and Doctor Strange have all played what other character?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdb", "question": "What L.A. Dodgers pitcher famously skipped his World Series starting assignment in 1965 because it fell on Yom Kippur?", "answer": "Sandy Koufax", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7353deec85e375820b247", "question": "Who said, \"I am prepared to meet my Maker. Whether my Maker is prepared for the ordeal of meeting me is another matter.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde5129c6c6b019850c9a8d", "question": "Who was the first King of the Northern Ten Tribes of Israel during the time of the Divided Kingdom?", "answer": "Jeroboam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "591c3512815febcc896f9259", "question": "In which country would you find the motor racing circuit called Kyalami?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae85eb74007905755f79e89", "question": "Shiitake, Enoki, Button, Porcini are all types of what?", "answer": "Mushrooms", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b3", "question": "Sharpshooter Phoebe Ann Mosey was better known as who?", "answer": "Annie Oakley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339215", "question": "Who voiced Rocky in the movie \"Chicken Run\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be580225415ba52ed6f0ab1", "question": "The TV show \"Soap\", was set in what fictional town?", "answer": "Dunn's River, Connecticut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2b", "question": "Which comic book and issue marked the first appearance of Wonder Woman?", "answer": "All Star Comics #8", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b9", "question": "The anti-depressant drug Fluoxetine is generally known by what other name?", "answer": "Prozac", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba256874c93a3298b2131", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Zeus place in the heavens as the constellation Ursa Major?", "answer": "Callisto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d4", "question": "What does the abbreviation VH1 stand for in the TV station by the same name?", "answer": "Video Hits 1", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb1", "question": "Comedy band Tenacious D took its name from what sportcaster's catchphrase for good defence?", "answer": "Marv Albert's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14b", "question": "Who caused the collapse of Barings Bank and inspired the film \"Rogue Trader\"?", "answer": "Nick Leeson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af22", "question": "George III of the United Kingdom was given what nickname?", "answer": "Farmer George", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14e", "question": "Arturo Toscanini played what instrument before conducting?", "answer": "The Cello", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595641ae803c1f1ebcc4a02a", "question": "The ball on top of a flag pole is called a what?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e57", "question": "What literary work inspired Police's \"Don't Stand So Close to Me\" song?", "answer": "Lolita", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398be", "question": "What superhero's enemies include the Joker, the Penguin and the Riddler?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358d4b5db0d66a186cb560", "question": "From which South American country do the beers \"Brahma\" and \"Antarctica\" come?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f28fff048f679a45aab9", "question": "During a tornado, what happens to air pressure?", "answer": "It drops", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339531", "question": "What show debuted in 1963 and became the longest running sci-fi series?", "answer": "Doctor Who", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec2", "question": "In what Irish city did Frank McCourt set his memoir \"Angela's Ashes\"?", "answer": "Limerick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a856", "question": "Which building houses the world's biggest four-faced chiming clock?", "answer": "Minneapolis City Hall", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c9ef0775fa611bce67f0", "question": "What breed of dog was used to popularize the phrase \"Yo quiero Taco Bell\"?", "answer": "Chihuahua -- Gidget, the 8-pound female Chihuahua, was only Taco Bell\u2019s mascot for 3 years, but she made the most of her time.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70e99f96e155acab35d3a", "question": "Who painted \"The Starry Night\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b5", "question": "What Shakespeare play if \"All the world's a stage\"?", "answer": "As You Like It", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f7453a9e54d890926f6f5", "question": "What is the longest river in Australia?", "answer": "The Murray River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8f", "question": "What William Boyd character headlined TV's first western?", "answer": "Hopalong Cassidy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b266", "question": "Which foot did Neil Armstrong first set on the moon?", "answer": "Left", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe937866bd93ce3a4e5f66f", "question": "Dentophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dentists", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601601a2fe83fe1f2a824c60", "question": "In what year were women first allowed to participate in the modern Olympic games?", "answer": "1900 -- in Paris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7c0a42b316f4693fb6798", "question": "What is the name for the process of electing a Pope?", "answer": "Conclave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339782", "question": "\"Skyrim\" is the fifth installment in which video game series?", "answer": "The Elder Scrolls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a952", "question": "What is the only US state that ends with the state's own postal abbreviation?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde49fec6c6b019850c9a71", "question": "Which two nations fought for control of North America in the French and Indian War?", "answer": "France and England", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65f211f3c0ead6880d635", "question": "Which President of South Africa ordered Nelson Mandela\u2019s release from prison?", "answer": "De Klerk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf9", "question": "What was the first building in the world to have more than 100 floors?", "answer": "Empire State Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad64", "question": "Who coached the US basketball \"Dream Team\" to a gold medal at the 1992 Barcelona Olympic Games?", "answer": "Chuck Daly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c027", "question": "What is \"military commander\" in Japanese?", "answer": "Shogun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e0f506d333868d34d723", "question": "What was the name given to the laws aimed at enforcing segregation in public places in the United States?", "answer": "Jim Crow Laws", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59bb2a52c9bff04efae6d75f", "question": "What is the birthname of author George Orwell?", "answer": "Eric Arthur Blair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971e1a689261e916c8e09b4", "question": "What were the Crusades?", "answer": " A series of religious wars", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b9", "question": "What actor plays the role of Evan Treborn in the movie \"The Butterfly Effect\"?", "answer": "Ashton Kucher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c5", "question": "In which Steven Spielberg movie does Audrey Hepburn star?", "answer": "Always", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ecafb24f84e0b9f9ffe9", "question": "What is a sphygmomanometer used to measure?", "answer": "Blood pressure", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da0", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Jones?", "answer": "Henry Fielding", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab39", "question": "Belgrade lies on the Danube and which other river?", "answer": "Sava", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388fd", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was warned that the cow was in the corn?", "answer": "Little Boy Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3c", "question": "Which element appears eighth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f5", "question": "What was the name of Ross' monkey in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Marcel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a89c", "question": "What is Greenland called by its Inuit native residents?", "answer": "Kaallalit Nunaat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc5", "question": "Ditra Flame was the \"Lady in Black\" who took thirteen red roses to what actor's grave every year?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b8", "question": "What word describes a handbag without straps or handles?", "answer": "Clutch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b53", "question": "Cate Blanchett received an Oscar nomination in 2008 for portraying what male musician?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the Springfield bowling alley?", "answer": "Barney's Bowl-A-Rama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8d", "question": "Which US president was born in Yorba Linda, California?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc39", "question": "What do the initials in O.J. Simpson's name stand for?", "answer": "Orenthal James", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae2", "question": "What 2002 movie has spawned sequels with the subtitles \"Apocalypse\", \"Extinction\", and \"Afterlife\"?", "answer": "Resident Evil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5a8c5dad637d903c8817", "question": "How many islands are in the so-called Thousand Islands area of the Saint Lawrence River?", "answer": "1,864", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c913", "question": "The amount of what substance in granite determines its color?", "answer": "Feldspar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339681", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Homer's middle name?", "answer": "Jay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef60f06ce05a3942286e4e", "question": "What did Clark Gable do four or more times a day?", "answer": "Shower", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3c", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The Shifting Reef\"?", "answer": "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b63b", "question": "What did Nestle freeze dry in 1938 that led to the development of powdered food products?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b3", "question": "Who performed the character of Miss Piggy until the early 2000's?", "answer": "Frank Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f3", "question": "What 1970 movie revolves around a cat named Duchess, her three kittens, and an evil butler named Edgar?", "answer": "The Aristocats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b36afb6c85e9e634ff42", "question": "Who released the song \"Fly Away\" at the end of 1998?", "answer": "Lenny Kravitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdc", "question": "What animal is said to have nurtured the founders of Rome, Romulus and Remus?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a903", "question": "What major river runs through the city of London?", "answer": "Thames", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ee47fe83fe1f2a824c08", "question": "What does parsley dipped in salt water on the Seder plate represent?", "answer": "Tears and pain of the Jewish slaves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b53906d333868d34d6e8", "question": "What rocket launched the Apollo program?", "answer": "Saturn rocket", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59db78a20ab2c8f322317ff5", "question": "John Downland was an English Renaissance composer for which instrument?", "answer": "The Lute", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab2", "question": "Karakul, Dorset, Urial, and Jacob are types of what?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b28a", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Bucephalus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd4", "question": "Who killed Count Dooku by cutting off his head?", "answer": "Anakin Skywalker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b571b6667df192a942e3368", "question": "What is the capital of Nicaragua?", "answer": "Managua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febbad27e83c707845b2146", "question": "Who was the first male African-American tennis player to win the U.S Open and the Wimbledon tournaments?", "answer": "Arthur Ashe (won the U.S. in 1968 and the Wimbledon in 1975)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba05", "question": "California's Mann's Chinese Theater is located on what street?", "answer": "Hollywood Boulevard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ba", "question": "What country is the \"land of the lions\"?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65f131f3c0ead6880d634", "question": "In ancient Greece, throwing an apple at someone was a declaration of what?", "answer": "Love", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb1be8df497e33de8057918", "question": "Who scored the first counted three-point basket in NBA history?", "answer": "Chris Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea4", "question": "Farnsworth Bentley became famous for holding whose umbrellas?", "answer": "Puff Daddy's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25984b63e5727cf5a484f", "question": "What year did Toni Braxton release the hit song \"Un-Break My Heart\"?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0adf0e662d71a53650fb5", "question": "Who became famous for painting New Mexico landscapes from her Model A Ford?", "answer": "Georgia O\u2019Keeffe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5af24be2844f4236002b95b1", "question": "How many countries does Afghanistan border?", "answer": "6", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4af", "question": "At what nation does Panama attach onto South America?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d47103f8e329de4f877897", "question": "What is the brewery featured in the British soap opera \"Coronation Street\"?", "answer": "Newton and Ridley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d115e14fea7fe947a2226b", "question": "Ernest Evans became famous under what name?", "answer": "Chubby Checker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339270", "question": "What is the name of the Alicia Keys backup singer who won season 2 of The Voice?", "answer": "Jermaine Paul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bd5afb6c85e9e634ff67", "question": "What is the atomic number of Antimony?", "answer": "51", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393dd", "question": "What is the real first name of the singer Boy George?", "answer": "George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bb96364247bf200fb8a5", "question": "What is a Karahi?", "answer": "A wok-like cooking pot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ea", "question": "\"The 10 days that shook the world\" refers to what country\u2019s revolution?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93dc86bd93ce3a4e5f6b9", "question": "How long is one Pluto year?", "answer": "248 Earth years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397be", "question": "What 1980's band had fans that happily called themselves \"blockheads\"?", "answer": "New Kids on the Block", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b4e601dd7bf43be5e7c9", "question": "What is the only US state with an official jelly?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a50", "question": "What 1973 single was Carly Simon\u2019s only single to top the Billboard charts?", "answer": "You're So Vain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3674ff048f679a45ab0e", "question": "What vegetable grows fast enough that you can hear it?", "answer": "Rhubarb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd41ee347d002c297e4ad", "question": "How many years did Nelson Mandela spend in prison?", "answer": "27 Years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ea77b24f84e0b9f9ffd4", "question": "Vermiphobia, helminthophobia, or scoleciphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Worms, especially parasitic ones", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd0a9ec223966ae8f88ba", "question": "In the movie \"The Martian\", where were the Mars exterior scenes shot?", "answer": "Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c430", "question": "What does the \"CAT\" in \"CAT scan\" stand for?", "answer": "Computerized Axial Tomography", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25835b63e5727cf5a4846", "question": "What was actually the \u201cweb\u201d in the first Spider-man wrist web-shooter toy introduced in the 1970s?", "answer": "String", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f52", "question": "What song begins with the words \"Betty, is that Jimmy's ring you're wearing?\"?", "answer": "Leader of the Pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f8befa5fdd6dd25324f1", "question": "Where is Queen Maud Land located?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7ced9877e98cb97778a47", "question": "What state is home to the Crazy Horse Memorial?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6002410a4be4723ccac2216e", "question": "In which branch of the arts is Katherine Dunham famous?", "answer": "Ballet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd9c97e83c707845b217d", "question": "According to legend, which music star did Michael Jordan once chastise for wearing the sneakers of a rival player/company?", "answer": "Bow Wow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf3", "question": "What two things are being compared in a stock's \"P/E ratio\"?", "answer": "Share price and earnings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f950fa5fdd6dd25324f6", "question": "What name is given to animals which only eat plants?", "answer": "Herbivores", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2592731a458464a93c46a", "question": "In what year was the NERF football created?", "answer": "1972 by former Minnesota Vikings' kicker Fred Cox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b0", "question": "What 1968 hit was the first to include the phrase \"heavy metal\" in its lyrics?", "answer": "Born to be Wild", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a008", "question": "What kind of dog is Pluto's girlfriend, Fifi?", "answer": "Pekingese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb5", "question": "Which type of nonsensical humorous verse was popularized by Edward Lear?", "answer": "Limerick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32b", "question": "Which character did Eddie Murphy play in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Reggie Hammond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae7", "question": "Who composed the Christmas carol \"Silent Night\"?", "answer": "Franz Xaver Gruber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8fc", "question": "Int the medical field, what do the initials E.E.G stand for?", "answer": "Electroencephalograph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c4", "question": "What is Mr. Sowerberry's job in Oliver Twist?", "answer": "Undertaker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03d", "question": "In 1969, what woman said \"No woman, in my time, will ever be Prime Minister\"?", "answer": "Margaret Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96ae623c87fd04dd15e16", "question": "Jeans are named for what European city?", "answer": "Genoa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb68d65ff7d326b622a97", "question": "The 1980s \"High Society\" was a musical remake of which 1930s play?", "answer": "The Philadelphia Story", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd6", "question": "Who was the messenger of the Roman Gods?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff14015b0ee8c595b6d3994", "question": "In what city was the Diary of Anne Frank written?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c2", "question": "NAFTA is a trade agreement between the US and what other two countries?", "answer": "Mexico and Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a7f720565ad31a57c7f1", "question": "What President\u2019s fondness for pork rinds made sales of the snack boom?", "answer": "George H. W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0c", "question": "What suit is the Queen is \"Alice's Adventures in Wonderland\"?", "answer": "Hearts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d47423f8e329de4f877899", "question": "How many litres does a Nebuchadnezzar contain?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32e", "question": "Most people breathe through one nostril at a time - True or False?", "answer": "True, over 85% of people breather through only one nostril at a time", "category": "science"}]